[
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### eom geanwyrde monuc⁠ — I am a professed monk",
        "correctAnswer": "ic",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the nominative so it remains 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt sægest (<em>þu</em>) ####, yrþlingc?⁠ — What say you, farmer?",
        "correctAnswer": "þu",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the nominative so it remains 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>he</em>) #### Noe gebletsade and his bearn⁠ — He blessed Noah and his child",
        "correctAnswer": "he",
        "explanation":"Here 'he' is used in the nominative so it remains 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Drihtnes ys eorðe, and eall þæt (<em>heo</em>) #### mid gefyld is⁠ — The earth is the Lord's, and all that she is filled with",
        "correctAnswer": "heo",
        "explanation":"Here 'heo' is used in the nominative so it remains 'heo'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>we</em>) #### cildra biddaþ þe, eala lareow, þæt þu tæce us sprecan leden⁠ — We children ask you, oh teacher, that you teach us to speak Latin",
        "correctAnswer": "we",
        "explanation":"Here 'we' is used in the nominative so it remains 'we'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif (<em>ge</em>) #### me ut adrifaþ fram eowrum geferscype ge etaþ wyrta eowre grene ond flæscmettas eowre hreawe⁠ — If you drive me away from your community you would eat your vegetables raw and your meat rare",
        "correctAnswer": "ge",
        "explanation":"Here 'ge' is used in the nominative so it remains 'ge'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>hie</em>) #### gretton hie gesybsumum wordum⁠ — They greeted them with words of peace",
        "correctAnswer": "hie",
        "explanation":"Here 'hie' is used in the nominative so it remains 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ealle þing (<em>ic</em>) #### synt gesealde⁠ — All things are given by me",
        "correctAnswer": "me",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the accusative so it becomes 'me'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We (<em>þu</em>) #### þanciaþ, þe þu hafest on gewealdum hiofen and eorþan⁠ — We thank you, you who has control of heaven and earth",
        "correctAnswer": "þe",
        "explanation":"Here 'þe' is used in the accusative so it becomes 'þe'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>he</em>) #### miclum gewundode⁠ — He wounded him severely",
        "correctAnswer": "hine",
        "explanation":"Here 'he' is used in the accusative so it becomes 'hine'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He geseah (<em>heo</em>) #### feorran⁠ — He saw her from afar",
        "correctAnswer": "heo",
        "explanation":"Here 'heo' is used in the accusative but feminine third person singular pronouns do not decline differently between nominiative and accusative so it stays as 'heo'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se abbod nerede (<em>we</em>) ####⁠ — The abbod saved us",
        "correctAnswer": "us",
        "explanation":"Here 'we' is used in the accusative so it becomes 'us'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic hiere (<em>ge</em>) #### Suþ-Dena folc⁠ — I hear you, people of the South-Danes",
        "correctAnswer": "eow",
        "explanation":"Here 'ge' is used in the accusative so it becomes 'eow'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie æt Tharse ðære byrig hie gemetton ond hie ða (<em>hie</em>) #### gecyston⁠ — They met one another at the city of Tarsus and they then kissed them",
        "correctAnswer": "hie",
        "explanation":"Here 'hie' is used in the accusative but third person plural pronouns do not decline differently between nominiative and accusative so it stays as 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwanon sylan scear oþþe culter, þe na gade hæfþ buton of cræfte (<em>ic</em>) ####?⁠ — How does the ploughman get his plough-share or knife or goad but by my craft? ",
        "correctAnswer": "min",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'min'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðonne þu and (<em>þu</em>) #### beoþ alysde⁠ — When you are yours are released",
        "correctAnswer": "þin",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'þin'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða he gefor ða feng (<em>he</em>) #### sunu to ðam rice⁠ — When he died then came his son to the throne",
        "correctAnswer": "his",
        "explanation":"Here 'he' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'his'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>heo</em>) #### hand nam and heo sona aras⁠ — He took her hand and she arose at once",
        "correctAnswer": "hire",
        "explanation":"Here 'heo' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'hire'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We sceolan syllan ðone teoþan dæl (<em>we</em>) #### worldspeda⁠ — We shall give the tenth portion of our world's goods",
        "correctAnswer": "ure",
        "explanation":"Here 'we' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'ure'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa Gotan eow hwon oferhergedon, and (<em>ge</em>) #### feawe ofslogon⁠ — The Ostrogoths ravaged you a little and slew a few of you",
        "correctAnswer": "eower",
        "explanation":"Here 'ge' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'eower'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða cuædon hie ðæt him nænig mæg leofra nære ðonne (<em>hie</em>) #### hlaford⁠ — Then they said that to them, no kinsman was dearer than their lord",
        "correctAnswer": "hira",
        "explanation":"Here 'hie' is used in the genitive so it becomes 'hira'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic be (<em>ic</em>) #### secge ðis sarspell⁠ — I tell this lament about myself",
        "correctAnswer": "me",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the dative so it becomes 'me'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic wille wiþ (<em>þu</em>) #### farnan, Ælfirc⁠ — I will go with you, Alfric",
        "correctAnswer": "þe",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the dative so it becomes 'þe'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se arcebiscop axode hyrsumnesse mid aþswerunge at (<em>he</em>) ####⁠ — The archbishop asked for obedience with an oath to him",
        "correctAnswer": "him",
        "explanation":"Here 'he' is used in the dative so it becomes 'him'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo spræc to (<em>heo</em>) #### selfre suna⁠ — She spoke to her own sons",
        "correctAnswer": "hire",
        "explanation":"Here 'heo' is used in the dative so it becomes 'hire'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ure fæder geaf to (<em>we</em>) #### feower bec fram feowerum foldan sceatum⁠ — Our father gave to us four books from the four corners of the world",
        "correctAnswer": "us",
        "explanation":"Here 'we' is used in the dative so it becomes 'us'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sibb sy mid (<em>ge</em>) ####⁠ — Peace be with ye",
        "correctAnswer": "eow",
        "explanation":"Here 'ge' is used in the dative so it becomes 'eow'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie woldon ða men (<em>hie</em>) #### to mete don⁠ — They wanted the men to make food for themselves",
        "correctAnswer": "heom",
        "explanation":"Here 'hie' is used in the dative so it becomes 'heom'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Abram cwæð to Lothe '(<em>ic</em>) #### sind gebroðru⁠ — Abraham said to Lot: 'We two are brothers'",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wit (<em>ic</em>) #### in ðære burnan baðodan⁠ — We two washed ourselves in that brook",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Crist þonne wat (<em>ic</em>) #### clænnyss⁠ — Christ is the water of our purity",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nu ic eom orwena ðæt (<em>ic</em>) #### seo eðylstæf afre weorþe gifede ætgædere⁠ — Now I am hopeless that the staff of our family will ever be given to us two together",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif (<em>þu</em>) #### ðæt fæsten fyre willaþ forstandan⁠ — If you two will protect that fastness from fire",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Swa (<em>þu</em>) #### se balewa het⁠ — So the baleful one commanded you two ",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic nu ðis þing write to ðe gemanelice and to minre meder and minum geswustrum forðon (<em>þu</em>) #### lufu sceal beon somod gemane⁠ — I now write this thing to you together, to my mother and my sister, because the love of you both shall be mutual ",
        "correctAnswer": "incer",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'incer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt wylle git ðæt ic (<em>þu</em>) #### do?⁠ — What do you two wish I do for you two?",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða wæron (<em>ic</em>) #### twegen on anum olfende þurh þæt rume westen⁠ — Then we two were on a camel travelling through that enormous desert",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### he bitere forgeald⁠ — He bitterly repaid us",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðanne gæornlicæ of þam god geþæncæ and for (<em>ic</em>) #### sawle geornlicæ beo⁠ — Remember God diligently from the property and be diligent for our two souls",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### is his hyldo þearf⁠ — for us two his favour is a necessity ",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>þu</em>) #### sindon bigswicon⁠ — You two are deceivers",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>þu</em>) #### forgeaf balewe geþohtas⁠ — He inspired you with wicked thoughts",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ac git waron æt þisse wydewan hame and þær þus (<em>þu</em>) #### lif leofodon⁠ — But you were at the home of a widow, and there passed your time in wisdom",
        "correctAnswer": "incer",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'incer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### her baru standaþ unwered wædo⁠ — we two stand here naked, unprotected by garments",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wit (<em>ic</em>) #### gefyldan niowes ceses⁠ — We filled ourselves with new cheese",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) Wit geseagon #### feond forwordene⁠ — We two saw our enemy perish",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) God mæg foreaðe #### æt foresceawian⁠ — God can very easily provide food for us two",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": " Gangaþ ut (<em>þu</em>) #### godwrecan⁠ — Come out ye two wretches",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>þu</em>) #### sceal worn fela maðma gemænra⁠ — To you two shall be a great many common treasures",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]